hallucinations. They're going to happen.
They're probably inherent to LLMs. So,
how do you avoid them and how do you
diagnose? Well, let's say you have some
kind of coding hallucination and what
you first need to say is was the
information available to the LLM in its
context window. People think that LLMs
are kind of like databases where they
store information and retrieve, but
that's absolutely not right. It's more
like they have a fuzzy JPEG of the
entirety of human knowledge. And so,
they know the basic shapes of things,
but they can't really tell you
specifics. And so, you have to basically
say was the information in context? If
it's not, then it's a factuality
hallucination. A factuality
hallucination is when it's attempting to
read something that you haven't passed
it and it just fails. It cannot recall
things. You should never trust an
unsourced LLM. So, the fix there is
obvious. You just load the information
into context. However, even if you pass
the agent the right context, it's not
always going to work. And so, you will
get a faithfulness hallucination where
it's not been faithful to the
information that you provided. Now, this
can sometimes happen because of
attention degradation where the context
window grows longer and longer and the
attention relationships get strained
between all the elements. So, the way to
get the agent out of that is to reduce
the number of tokens in its context
window. So, you reduce the number of
attention relationships and it can focus
better. When you're deep in the context
window and there's lots of attention
degradation, I call that the dumb zone.
So, the cure for faithfulness is to
somehow get out of the dumb zone. That
might be clearing the context, that
might be running compact, that might be
handing off to a separate session.
Hallucinations are here to stay and so,
you need to know how to deal with them.